Okay, so we need to start by solving the issue of, we are losing all of our spaces when we have all of our spans here.
So you can look, for example, this span that has a space, you can actually see that it is zero by zero.
If you look up here, I can't have the mouse there at the same time, but if you look up there, it is zero by zero, meaning it has no width.
I can actually show you right here if you scroll down, zero by zero.
So I would challenge you to try to pause the video and see if you can figure out how to fix this issue.
Okay, so it might actually be a simpler fix than you might think.
Basically what we need to do is we need to add in a minimum width and it's going to be 14 pixels.
So this is why it was so important to use a mono space font because all of the characters and all of the spaces should be basically the same width.
You see if I hover over knee, you can see that it's 14.45 pixels wide and so is every other letter, even in a letter like I, which might be smaller in other fonts, is the same 14.45 pixels and then therefore we just need to add a minimum width of 14 pixels to our spaces.
Okay, so we can go into our CSS and make that change.
So I'm just going to do it below my button hover here and we will just target all spans and we're going to give them a min width of 14 pixels.
Okay, so let's go back and check that out and there you go.
It is working.
Awesome.
Okay, moving on from here, you'll notice that if I were to keep typing, that I can keep going and the text is not moving.
So that is a problem.
I can't see the rest of the text.
So the next thing we need to do is be able to scroll our container, but we also only want to scroll our container when we get about to the middle here, which to me is about 20 pixels.
So let's take a look at how we can do that in our JavaScript.
We're also going to go ahead and we can remove our console log here for now.
I think we get the idea behind that and we'll go below here and we'll comment out.
This is to scroll the container only after 20 characters.
So if our total typed dot length is greater than or equal to 20 pixels, so anything over, sorry, 20 characters, then we're going to set a constant for a scroll amount.
And this is going to be equal to our total typed and we'll put this in brackets, total typed dot length minus 20 bracket.
So what this means is if we were at 100, we only want to have scrolled 80 times.
We don't want to scroll the first 20.
So that's why we have our total type length minus 20 and then from there, we're going to multiply with our asterisks and then 14.
So that means we want to actually scroll by 14 pixels times however many times we have scrolled at this point.
Okay, and then our text container, we're going to use the scroll left property and we're going to set our scroll amount.
Okay, so let's go ahead and check that out.
Okay, so I'm going to start typing and you can see that we are scrolling awesome, so I'll just keep typing randomly.
Okay, and you can see that that is working perfectly.
Okay, and let's go ahead and actually test our backspace as well to make sure that it's yeah, it's scrolling backwards and everything.
So we can actually probably take this all the way back to the beginning.
So our backspace works and our scroll works.
Okay, that's awesome.
And eventually this caught up.
Okay, great.
You'll see it even removed the correct or error spans from all of these as well.
Okay, so that allows you to have that second chance if you do make an error.
Speaking of errors, let's just make sure we're going to console log our errors and just make sure that that's correct.
That's going to be important because we want to be able to track these for our scoring.
So I'm just going to console log my errors here and we'll go back into our console this time and you'll see that I have a lot of errors.
So you have 22 errors, but if I backspace, it actually makes that number go down.
So if you do miss one, you are able to backspace to fix it.
Okay, nice.
Okay, so from there we're going to remove this console log for now.
And we're pretty much done with this functionality for handling all of our keystrokes.
Okay, so now you might have noticed that we don't have a timer that works.
So in the next one, we're going to focus on our logic to start our timer and it as well as calculate our words per minute.
Okay, I'll see you in that one.
Bye for now.